<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<XML_DIZ_INFO>
	<MASTER_PAD_VERSION_INFO>
		<MASTER_PAD_VERSION>3.11</MASTER_PAD_VERSION>
		<MASTER_PAD_EDITOR>PADGen 3.1.1.50 http://www.padgen.org</MASTER_PAD_EDITOR>
		<MASTER_PAD_INFO>Portable Application Description, or PAD for short, is a data set that is used by shareware authors to disseminate information to anyone interested in their software products. To find out more go to http://pad.asp-software.org</MASTER_PAD_INFO>
	</MASTER_PAD_VERSION_INFO>
	<Company_Info>
		<Company_Name>Flachmann und Heggelbacher GmbH &amp; Co. KG</Company_Name>
		<Address_1>Waldkirchbogen 27</Address_1>
		<Address_2 />
		<City_Town>Neuried</City_Town>
		<State_Province />
		<Zip_Postal_Code>D-82061</Zip_Postal_Code>
		<Country>Germany</Country>
		<Company_WebSite_URL>http://fuh-edv.de</Company_WebSite_URL>
		<Contact_Info>
			<Author_First_Name>Oliver</Author_First_Name>
			<Author_Last_Name>Heggelbacher</Author_Last_Name>
			<Author_Email>info@docklight.de</Author_Email>
			<Contact_First_Name>Oliver</Contact_First_Name>
			<Contact_Last_Name>Heggelbacher</Contact_Last_Name>
			<Contact_Email>info@docklight.de</Contact_Email>
		</Contact_Info>
		<Support_Info>
			<Sales_Email>info@docklight.de</Sales_Email>
			<Support_Email>support@docklight.de</Support_Email>
			<General_Email>info@docklight.de</General_Email>
			<Sales_Phone>+49 89-38169745-0</Sales_Phone>
			<Support_Phone>+49 89-38169745-0</Support_Phone>
			<General_Phone>+49 89-38169745-0</General_Phone>
			<Fax_Phone>+49 89-38169745-9</Fax_Phone>
		</Support_Info>
	</Company_Info>
	<Program_Info>
		<Program_Name>Docklight RS232 Terminal - RS232 Monitor</Program_Name>
		<Program_Version>2.4.11</Program_Version>
		<Program_Release_Month>03</Program_Release_Month>
		<Program_Release_Day>22</Program_Release_Day>
		<Program_Release_Year>2023</Program_Release_Year>
		<Program_Cost_Dollars>75</Program_Cost_Dollars>
		<Program_Cost_Other_Code>EUR</Program_Cost_Other_Code>
		<Program_Cost_Other>69</Program_Cost_Other>
		<Program_Type>Shareware</Program_Type>
		<Program_Release_Status>Minor Update</Program_Release_Status>
		<Program_Install_Support>Install and Uninstall</Program_Install_Support>
		<Program_OS_Support>Windows 11,Windows 10,Windows 8,Win7 x32,Win7 x64</Program_OS_Support>
		<Program_Language>English</Program_Language>
		<Program_Change_Info>optimized CPU use</Program_Change_Info>
		<Program_Specific_Category>Development Tools</Program_Specific_Category>
		<Program_Category_Class>Development::Debugging</Program_Category_Class>
		<Program_System_Requirements>COM port(s) available</Program_System_Requirements>
		<File_Info>
			<File_Size_Bytes>6481456</File_Size_Bytes>
			<File_Size_K>6330</File_Size_K>
			<File_Size_MB>6.18</File_Size_MB>
		</File_Info>
		<Expire_Info>
			<Has_Expire_Info>Y</Has_Expire_Info>
			<Expire_Count>99999999</Expire_Count>
			<Expire_Based_On>Days</Expire_Based_On>
			<Expire_Other_Info>limited functionality in evaluation version</Expire_Other_Info>
			<Expire_Month />
			<Expire_Day />
			<Expire_Year />
		</Expire_Info>
	</Program_Info>
	<Program_Descriptions>
		<English>
			<Keywords>rs232,rs-232,docklight,rs232 terminal,rs232 monitor,com port,serial port,virtual com,serial,communication,communications,logger,analyzer,sniffer,terminal,serial,analyzer,hex,rs485,rs422,rs232 tester,rs232 debugger,protocol tester,logging</Keywords>
			<Char_Desc_45>RS232 Terminal / RS232 Monitor</Char_Desc_45>
			<Char_Desc_80>Test, analysis and simulation for serial communication protocols (RS232, ...)</Char_Desc_80>
			<Char_Desc_250>Docklight is a testing, analysis and simulation tool for serial communication protocols (RS232, RS485/422 and others). * Simulating serial protocols * Logging RS232 data * Detecting specific data sequences * Responding to incoming data</Char_Desc_250>
			<Char_Desc_450>Docklight is a testing, analysis and simulation tool for serial communication protocols (RS232, RS485/422 and others). It allows you to monitor the communication between two serial devices or to test the serial communication of a single device. Key functions include: * Simulating serial protocols * Logging RS232 data * Detecting specific data sequences * Responding to incoming data.</Char_Desc_450>
			<Char_Desc_2000>Docklight is a testing, analysis and simulation tool for serial communication protocols (RS232, RS485/422 and others). It allows you to monitor the communication between two serial devices or to test the serial communication of a single device. Docklight is easy to use and runs on almost any standard PC using Windows 10 / 8 / 7. Key functions include: 
  * Simulating serial protocols - Docklight can send out user-defined sequences according to the protocol used and it can react to incoming sequences. This makes it possible to simulate the behavior of a serial communication device, which is particularly useful for generating test conditions that are hard to reproduce with the original device (e.g. problem conditions). 
  * Logging RS232 data - All serial communication data can be logged using two different file formats: use plain text format for fast logging and storing huge amounts of data. Or create a HTML file with styled text that lets you easily distinguish between incoming and outgoing data or additional information. 
  * Detecting specific data sequences - In many test cases you will need to check for a specific sequence within the RS232 data that indicates a problem condition. Docklight manages a list of such data sequences for you and is able to perform user-defined actions after detecting a sequence, e.g. taking a snapshot of all communication data before and after the error message was received.
  * Responding to incoming data - Docklight lets you specify user-defined answers to the different communication sequences received. This allows you to build a basic simulator for your serial device within a few minutes. It can also help you to trace a certain error by sending out a diagnostics command after receiving the error message.
  * Docklight has been successfully tested with many popular USB-to-RS232 converters, virtual null modem software, and many other Embedded Development tools that appear as a virtual COM port.</Char_Desc_2000>
		</English>
		<German>
			<Keywords>rs232,rs-232,docklight,rs232 terminal,rs232 monitor,com port,serial port,virtual com,serial,communication,communications,logger,analyzer,sniffer,terminal,serial,analyzer,hex,rs485,rs422,rs232 tester,rs232 debugger,protocol tester,logging</Keywords>
			<Char_Desc_45>RS232 Terminal / RS232 Monitor</Char_Desc_45>
			<Char_Desc_80>Test-, Analyse- und Simulations-Werkzeug für serielle Protokolle (RS232 u.a.)</Char_Desc_80>
			<Char_Desc_250>Docklight ist ein Test-, Analyse- und Simulations-Werkzeug für serielle Kommunikationsprotokolle (RS232 u.a.).  * Simulation serieller Protokolle  * Protokollieren von RS232-Daten  * Aufspüren spezieller Sequenzen  * Auf empfangene Daten antworten</Char_Desc_250>
			<Char_Desc_450>Docklight ist ein Test-, Analyse- und Simulations-Werkzeug für serielle Kommunikationsprotokolle (RS232, RS485/422 u.a.). Es wird zur Überwachung der Kommunikation zwischen zwei seriellen Geräten eingesetzt oder um die serielle Kommunikation eines einzelnen Geräts zu testen. Grundfunktionen:  * Simulation serieller Protokolle  * Protokollieren von RS232-Daten  * Aufspüren spezieller Sequenzen  * Auf empfangene Daten antworten</Char_Desc_450>
			<Char_Desc_2000>Docklight ist ein Test-, Analyse- und Simulations-Werkzeug für serielle Kommunikationsprotokolle (RS232, RS485/422 u.a.). Es wird zur Überwachung der Kommunikation zwischen zwei seriellen Geräten eingesetzt oder um die serielle Kommunikation eines einzelnen Geräts zu testen. Docklight ist einfach zu bedienen und läuft auf fast allen Standard-PCs unter Windows 10 / 8 / 7.
  * Simulation serieller Protokolle - Mit Docklight können frei definierbare Sequenzen eines Kommunikationsprotokolls gesendet werden. Docklight kann auf eine empfangene Sequenz reagieren und eine benutzerdefinierte Reaktion aussenden. Dies ermöglicht die Simulation eines seriellen Geräts bzw. dessen Verhalten. Insbesondere können so Testbedingungen simuliert werden, die mit dem Originalgerät schwer zu reproduzieren sind, z.B. Fehlfunktionen.
  * Protokollieren von RS232-Daten - Alle seriellen Kommunikationsdaten können protokolliert werden, entweder in einem Standard-Textformat (hohe Verarbeitungsgeschwindigkeit), oder in HTML-Format mit farblicher Kennzeichnung.
  * Aufspüren spezieller Sequenzen - In vielen Test-Szenarios sollen besondere Sequenzen innerhalb des RS232-Datenstroms erkannt werden, welche auf ein Problem hinweisen. Docklight erlaubt Ihnen, eine Liste solcher Datensequenzen zu verwalten und Aktionen festzulegen, die Docklight nach dem Empfang einer Sequenz ausführen soll. Sie können z.B. einen Schnappschuss der RS232-Kommunikationsdaten vor und nach dem Empfang eines Fehlercodes aufnehmen.
  * Auf empfangene Daten antworten - Mit Docklight können benutzerdefinierte Antworten auf die unterschiedlichen Empfangssequenzen definiert werden. So können Sie in wenigen Minuten einen einfachen Simulator für ein serielles Gerät zusammenstellen. Oder Sie können nach dem Empfang eines Fehlercodes ein spezielles Diagnosekommando an Ihr serielles Gerät schicken, um die Fehlerursache zu finden.
  * Docklight wurde mit verschiedenen USB-nach-RS232-Konvertern erfolgreich getestet.</Char_Desc_2000>
		</German>
		<French>
			<Keywords>rs232,rs-232,docklight,com,monitor,serial,sniffer,terminal,rs485,rs422,tester,logger,communication série,analyseur de protocole,simulateur de protocole,monitorer liaison série,espionner liaison série,testeur de protocole,simulateur de protocole</Keywords>
			<Char_Desc_45>Terminal RS232 / Moniteur RS232</Char_Desc_45>
			<Char_Desc_80>Tester/analyser/simuler des protocoles de communication série (RS232 et autres)</Char_Desc_80>
			<Char_Desc_250>Tester/analyser/simuler des protocoles de communication série (RS232, RS485...). * Simulation de protocoles séries * Enregistrement des données transitant via une liaison RS232 * Détection de séquences de données spécifiques * Réponses automatiques</Char_Desc_250>
			<Char_Desc_450>Docklight est un utilitaire qui permet de tester/analyser et simuler des protocoles de communication série (RS232, RS485/422 et autres).  * Simulation de protocoles séries  * Enregistrement des données transitant via une liaison RS232  * Détection de séquences de données spécifiques  * Réponses automatiques à des données entrantes.</Char_Desc_450>
			<Char_Desc_2000>Docklight est un utilitaire qui permet de tester/analyser et simuler des protocoles de communication série (RS232, RS485/422..). Il peut être utilisé pour observer la communication entre deux appareils ou pour tester/valider le protocole de communication série d'un appareil seul. Docklight est simple d'utilisation et peut être exécuté sur pratiquement tout PC standard utilisant un système d'exploitation Windows 10 / 8 / 7.  
  * Simulation de protocoles séries - Docklight peut être utilisé pour émettre des séquences prédéfinies en fonction du protocole de communication utilisé afin d'observer la réaction de l'appareil connecté. Docklight peut aussi réagir automatiquement sur des séquences entrantes; ceci permettra entre autre de simuler le comportement d'une communication série d'un appareil
afin de tester par exemple un logiciel connecté.
  * Enregistrement des données transitant via une liaison RS232 - Les données d'une communication série peuvent être espionnées et enregistrées dans deux format de fichiers différents: un format texte dont l'enregistrement sur le disque sera très rapide et qui permettra la traçabilité d'un flot de données importants, un format HTML dont les couleurs permettront de reconnaître simplement le sens de transit des données ainsi que les différentes informations éventuellement ajoutées par Docklight.
  * Détection de séquences de données spécifiques - Dans certains cas d'utilisation vous pouvez être amenés à devoir détecter des séquences spécifiques transitant via la liaison série. Docklight permet la définition d'une liste de séquences et vous permet d'effectuer une liste d'actions lorsqu'une telle séquence est détectée.
  * Réponses automatiques à des données entrantes - Docklight vous permet de spécifier des réponses à différentes séquences entrantes. Ceci vous permet de créer une simulation basique de la partie communication d'un appareil.
  * Docklight à été testé avec succès avec plusieurs convertisseurs USB-RS232.</Char_Desc_2000>
		</French>
	</Program_Descriptions>
	<Web_Info>
		<Application_URLs>
			<Application_Info_URL>http://docklight.de</Application_Info_URL>
			<Application_Order_URL>http://docklight.de/shop_en.htm</Application_Order_URL>
			<Application_Screenshot_URL>http://docklight.de/img/docklight_screenshot.png</Application_Screenshot_URL>
			<Application_Icon_URL>http://docklight.de/img/docklight_icon_32x32.png</Application_Icon_URL>
			<Application_XML_File_URL>http://docklight.de/padfiles/docklpad.xml</Application_XML_File_URL>
		</Application_URLs>
		<Download_URLs>
			<Primary_Download_URL>http://docklight.de/download/Docklight.zip</Primary_Download_URL>
			<Secondary_Download_URL>http://fuh-edv.de/docklight/download/Docklight.zip</Secondary_Download_URL>
			<Additional_Download_URL_1 />
			<Additional_Download_URL_2 />
		</Download_URLs>
	</Web_Info>
	<Permissions>
		<Distribution_Permissions>Flachmann und Heggelbacher
Software Distribution Agreement:

Copyright Flachmann und Heggelbacher GmbH &amp; Co. KG (www.fuh-edv.de) 
and Kickdrive Software Solutions (www.kickdrive.de)

The evaluation version of this software may be freely distributed, with exceptions noted below, provided the distribution package (.zip file) is not modified. No person or company may charge a fee for the distribution of this software product without written permission from the copyright holder. This software product may not be bundled or distributed with any other package without written permission of the copyright holder.

THE EVALUATION VERSION OF THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. 
IN NO EVENT SHALL "FLACHMANN UND HEGGELBACHER" OR ITS CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.</Distribution_Permissions>
		<EULA>fuh_license_int_web.txt

Flachmann und Heggelbacher
Software End User License Agreement
For 1 (one) Computer

NOTICE TO USER:
THIS IS A CONTRACT BETWEEN YOU AND "FLACHMANN UND HEGGELBACHER"
("FuH"), A COMPANY LOCATED IN NEURIED, GERMANY. BY
INDICATING YOUR ACCEPTANCE BELOW, YOU ACCEPT ALL THE TERMS AND
CONDITIONS OF THIS AGREEMENT. This License Agreement
accompanies a FuH software product ("Software") and related
explanatory written materials ("Documentation"). This copy of
the Software is licensed to you as the end user or to your
employer or another third party authorized to permit your use
of the Software.  "You" as used in the remainder of this
License Agreement refers to the licensee.

Upon your acceptance of this Agreement, FuH grants to you a non-
exclusive license to use the Software and Documentation,
provided that you agree to the following:

1. Use of the Software.
* You may install and use the Software on a single computer.
* Personal Use: The primary user of each computer on which the
Software is installed may also install and use the Software on
one portable or home computer.  However, the Software may not
be used on the secondary computer by another person at the same
time the Software on the primary computer is being used.

2. Copyright. The Software is the intellectual property of FuH
and their partners and is protected by German copyright law,
international treaty provisions, and applicable laws of the
country in which it is being used. Any copies that you are
permitted to make pursuant to this Agreement must contain the
same copyright and other proprietary notices that appear on or
in the Software. 

3. Transfer.  You may not rent, lease, sublicense, or lend the
Software or Documentation. You may, however, transfer all your
rights to use the Software to another person or legal entity
provided that you transfer this Agreement, the Software,
including all copies, updates and prior versions, and all
Documentation to such person or entity and that you retain no
copies, including copies stored on a computer.

4. Limited Warranty.    FuH warrants to you that the Software
will perform substantially in accordance with the Documentation
for the ninety (90) day period following your receipt of the
Software. To make a warranty claim, you must return the
Software to the location where you obtained it along with a
copy of your sales receipt within such ninety (90) day period.
If the Software does not perform substantially in accordance
with the Documentation, the entire and exclusive liability of
FuH and their partners, and your exclusive remedy shall be
limited to either, at FuH's option, the replacement of the
Software or the refund of the license fee you paid for the
Software.

FuH AND THEIR PARTNERS DO NOT AND CANNOT WARRANT THE PERFORMANCE
OR RESULTS YOU MAY OBTAIN BY USING THE SOFTWARE OR
DOCUMENTATION.  THE FOREGOING STATES THE SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE
REMEDIES FOR FuH'S OR ITS SUPPLIERS' BREACH OF WARRANTY.
EXCEPT FOR THE FOREGOING LIMITED WARRANTY, FuH AND ITS
SUPPLIERS MAKE NO WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED,
AS TO NONINFRINGEMENT OF THIRD PARTY RIGHTS, MERCHANTABILITY,
OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE. IN NO EVENT WILL FuH OR
ITS SUPPLIERS BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR ANY CONSEQUENTIAL,
INCIDENTAL OR SPECIAL DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY LOST PROFITS OR
LOST SAVINGS, EVEN IF AN FuH REPRESENTATIVE HAS BEEN ADVISED OF
THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, OR FOR ANY CLAIM BY ANY THIRD
PARTY.

Some states or jurisdictions do not allow the exclusion or
limitation of incidental, consequential or special damages, or
the exclusion of implied warranties or limitations on how long
an implied warranty may last, so the above limitations may not
apply to you. To the extent permissible, any implied warranties
are limited to ninety (90) days. This warranty gives you
specific legal rights. You may have other rights which vary
from state to state or jurisdiction to jurisdiction. For
further warranty information, please contact FuH's Customer
Support Department.

5. General Provisions.  If any part of this Agreement is found
void and unenforceable, it will not affect the validity of the
balance of the Agreement, which shall remain valid and
enforceable according to its terms. This Agreement shall
automatically terminate upon failure by you to comply with its
terms. This Agreement may only be modified in writing signed by
an authorized officer of FuH.
</EULA>
	</Permissions>
</XML_DIZ_INFO>
